So when we visualize data, we're plotting the data.
当我们做数据可视化时 我们在对数据进行绘图
And then we need to figure out what we're going to use to represent each piece
然后要弄清楚 以什么方式去展现
of data.
每条数据
That piece of data we're going to call a glyph
在数据可视化中 被可视化出来的一条数据
when it's represented visually as part of a data visualization.
被称作一个图元
So as we saw before, charts display data, and the choice of chart and the elements
如前所述，图表可以展现数据 如何选择图表和图表元素
of a chart are often dependent on the kinds of data that we want to indicate.
则取决于我们想要表现的数据
We can use glyphs in charts to further display data, either new data or
在图表中，我们可以用图元 来更好地展现新数据
to reinforce existing data.
和强化已有的数据
For example, the shapes at the top of a bar chart, or the actual shapes of
例如 柱形图顶端的图形 或者柱形图里面的柱形
the bars in a bar chart or a Gantt chart can change based on the data.
或者Gantt （甘特） 图中的柱形 都可以根据数据而改变
In this case, the thickness of the bars can change based on the data value.
这种情况下 柱形的宽度可以 根据数据的值来定
If we're plotting a line chart or a scatter chart,
如果我们要画折线图或散点图
we can use different values for the data points, different glyphs to represent
可以用不同的值表达数据点 用不同的图元来展现
different values of the data points of yet a third variable.
不同的数据点 用上第三个变量
Tables, as you're plotting two nominal values here, two categories, and
在表格中 你展示的是 两个轴向和类别的数据
looking at the intersection of those two categories we can plot yet
在这两个类别轴的交汇处 我们可以使用
a third variable based on the shape or other decorations of the values.
第三个变量来展现数值的 不同形状或特征
So glyphs are items that indicate data points in a chart or a data visualization,
图元是图表或者 可视化图形中的数据点
and they have other dimensions that they can use to encode other measures.
它们还会有其他维度 可以用来描绘其他的量度
So for example, here is a simulation of a tornado
例如 这里有个龙卷风的模拟
that's part of a presentation visualization at the NCSA.
这是NCSA的可视化展示的一部分
And on the ground we have an array, basically a grid of cones laid out.
在地面上有这么一个阵列 像是满地锥体网装展开
And these cones are glyphs that are indicating
这些锥体就是图元
the ground wind speed and direction.
表示地面的风向和风速
And so speed is being mapped to the length of the cone, and
这里，速度被映射到 锥体的长度上
length is a good perceptual indicator of a quantitative value.
而长度用来表达数值量 很直观
And then we have the direction, the wind direction is the orientation of the cone.
还有风向 风向用锥体的朝向来表示
And ordinarily, we wouldn't care about any one direction being greater than another,
一般情况下 我们不关心 哪个方向比另一方向更密集
but we're using the differences in wind direction from one cone to another
但这里 我们用不同锥体之间 方向的不同
in order to indicate convergence or divergence of the wind.
来表示风的散度或者旋度
And so, we're using perspective here.
所以这里用到了透视
So we can see some of the details of the cones here in the forefront,
这样我们就可以看到 近处锥体的细节
and then we can see some textures in the background.
以及远处的纹理
And then you can see some color changes in these glyphs.
你也可以看到锥体颜色的变化
These cones are being coded in color.
这些锥体用颜色做了标记
If they're orange, it represents an updraft, and
橙色表示上升气流
if they're in blue, then it's a downdraft.
蓝色表示下沉气流
And so we're using color to emphasize
我们用颜色来强调
a directional change in a particularly important direction of up or down.
在某个重要方向上的方向变化 这里就是指上下的变化
And so these glyphs give us the opportunity to encode additional
这些图元让我们得以通过 使用额外的变量
data variables in what would ordinarily be just a two dimensional chart
让通常只是平面上的二维图表
here on the ground of this three-dimensional visualization.
变成这样的三维可视化图
So in terms of our analysis of perceptual effectiveness,
所以 我们对感知有效性的分析
we're mapping quantitative values.
实际上就是分析数值量 和图元间的映射
For example, wind speed and wind direction as length and angle.
例如，风速和风向映射到 长度和角度上
And direction as a quantitative value,
而风向也是个数值量
because we're looking at the differences between neighboring points quantitatively.
因为我们要看的是 相邻点之间数值上的变化
We have some nominal values that we're mapping.
我们也会映射一些类别量
For example, updrafts or downdrafts are being mapped as hue.
比如 上升和下降气流的差异 被映射为色相的差异
We're not saying that one is greater than the other,
这里不是要表示 一个量比另一个更大
just that they're different categories,
只是表示它们是两个 不同的类别
fundamental categories of wind direction, whether the wind is going up or down.
是风向很基本的分类 无论风向是朝上还是朝下
And we're mapping that to hue,
我们把这一点映射到色相上
which is a very effective use of a mapping value to a data value.
这是个非常有用的映射方法
And then finally, the shape is nominal in the fact that if I go back to the original
最后，形状差异也可作为 映射中类别量
slide, the actual particles are being mapped with spheres and cylinders.
如初始的讲稿中 将粒子映射成球或者圆柱体
Whereas, the wind speed on the ground is being mapped with a cone.
然而本例中 地面的风被映射成锥体
And so that shape difference Is another nominal indication that you're looking at
所以形状的差异也可以 用于类别的表示
data from ground wind speed versus airborne wind speeds from the particles.
如从粒子角度展示了 地面风速与空中风速的差异
So you can map other data too.
你也可以据此映射其他变量
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community